We believe what you say, Captain Kirk, but our position has not altered.
寇克船长，我们相信你，但我们不会改变立场
The Halkan Council cannot permit your Federation
哈克委员会不会允许
to mine dilithium crystals on our planet.
联邦在这里开采双锂晶体
We have shown the council historical proof that our missions are peaceful.
我们已向委员会证明这些任务是为了和平
We accept that your Federation is benevolent at present,
我们相信你的联邦目前是仁慈的
but the future is always in question.
但是未来无法预见
Our dilithium crystals represent awesome power.
双锂晶体力量惊人
Wrongful use of that power, even to the extent of the taking of one life,
如果错误使用这种力量，即使只伤害一个人
would violate our history of total peace.
也会违背我们和平处事的传统
To prevent that, we would die, captain, as a race, if necessary.
舰长，为了杜绝这种事，我们宁愿灭族
I admire your ethics
我敬佩你高尚的品德
and hope to prove ours.
我们自己也很高尚
- Kirk to Enterprise. - Spock here.
- 寇克呼叫进取号 - 我是史波克
Report on magnetic storm, Mr. Spock.
史波克先生，报告电磁风暴状况
Standard ion type, captain, but quite violent...
舰长，电磁风暴没有扩大，但是相当剧烈…
- and unpredictable.
并且不可预测
- Rough ride? - If we stay.
- 传送危险吗？ - 是的，如果我们不尽早离开
Stand by to beam up landing party.
准备回收地面队伍
Plot an extended orbit to clear disturbance. Kirk out.
驾驶飞船到外层轨道上避免干扰，通话结束
- Comply, Mr. Sulu. - Aye, sir.
- 苏鲁先生，执行命令 - 是的，长官
When may we resume discussion?
我们什么时候能恢复谈判？
The council will meditate further. But do not be hopeful of any change.
委员会会继续协商的，但是别抱希望
Captain.
舰长
You do have the might to force the crystals from us, of course.
你可以逼我们交出晶体
But we won't. Consider that.
但是我们不会那么做，好好考虑吧
Enterprise. Transporter Room, energise.
进取号，传送室，开始传送
Trouble, sir.
有麻烦了，长官
Spock was right. It was a rough ri...
史波克说对了，这真是次危险的…
At norm, Mr. Kyle. Controls at neutral.
按照惯例，卡尔先生，半自动控制
Yes, sir.
是的，长官
Status of mission, captain?
长官，任务执行的怎么样了？
- No change. - Standard procedure, captain?
- 没有进展 - 舰长，标准程序？
Mr. Sulu, you will program phaser barrage on Halkan cities.
苏鲁先生，将相位炮对准哈克的城市
Yes, Mr. Spock.
是的，史波克先生
- Their military capability, captain? - None.
- 舰长，他们的武装如何？ - 他们没有武装
Regrettable that this society has chosen suicide.
真遗憾，这个星球上的人选择要自杀
Mr. Kyle, you were instructed to compensate during the ion storm.
卡尔先生，遇到电磁风暴应该集中精神
- But I tried... - Carelessness with the equipment
- 但是我尽力了… - 漫不经心地操作设备
- cannot be tolerated. - But, Mr. Spock, I tried...
- 是不能容忍的 - 但是，史波克先生，我尽力了…
- Your agoniser. - No, Mr. Spock.
- 交出你的电击器 - 不，史波克先生
- Your agoniser, please.
- 给我电击器
I tried, I really tried.
我尽力了，我真的尽力了
Space, the final frontier.
宇宙，最后的边疆
These are the voyages of the starship Enterprise.
这是星舰进取号的航程
Its five-year mission: To explore strange new worlds,
它的五年任务，是去探索未知的新世界
to seek out new life and new civilisations,
找寻新的生命与新的文明
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
勇敢的航向前人未至之境
Captain's log, stardate unknown.
舰长日志，未知星历
During an ion storm, my landing party has beamed back to the Enterprise
在一场电磁风暴中，登陆队伍被传回进取号
and found it and the personnel aboard changed.
但是发现飞船和上面的人员都变了
The ship is subtly altered, physically.
飞船外型上也有了微妙的变化
Behaviour and discipline has become brutal, savage.
行为和纪律也变得残酷、野蛮
Mr. Scott, the storm has caused some minor damage in your section.
史考特，电磁暴对你的部门造成了轻微损伤
There are also injuries requiring your attention, doctor.
医生，有一些人员受伤，需要你关注
Well, gentlemen?
怎么样，先生们？
- Mr. Spock. - Yes?
- 史波克先生 - 什么情况？
The power beam jumped for a moment, sir,
长官，在登陆队伍被传送到飞船上时
just as the landing party was about to materialise.
能量流发生了短暂跳动
- I never saw it happen before. - Due to your error, Mr. Kyle?
- 我从来没见过这种情况 - 这都是因为你的操作失误，卡尔先生
No, Mr. Spock. Before.
不，史波克
Possibly a result of the severe storm. Captain.
舰长，这或许是电磁风暴太强烈导致的
- Do you feel any abnormal effects? - Yes.
- 你感觉到什么异常吗？ - 是的
Dr. McCoy, you better look us over. That was a rough beam-up.
麦考伊医生，最好给我们做一次彻底检查 这次传送很惊险
Yes, sir.
好的，长官
Mr. Spock, have those transporter circuits checked.
史波克先生，安排检查下传送装置是否正常
- What is all this? - How did we get in this..?
- 这是什么情况？ - 我们怎么会这样…？
Not now. Not now.
现在不要讨论
What is this?
这是什么情况？
Everything's all messed up, changed around, out of place.
所有事情都改变了，让人无法接受
Captain, what's happened?
舰长，到底发生了什么？
Well, not everything. That spot, I spilled acid there a year ago.
并不是所有事情，这个污点去年就有了
- Jim, what in blazes..? - I don't know.
- 吉姆，这到底是…？ - 我不知道
It's our Enterprise...
这确实是我们的进取号…
...but it isn't.
…但又不是
- Maybe... - Maybe what, captain?
- 或许… - 或许什么，舰长？
Any of you feel dizzy when we were in the transporter beam?
传送时你们有没有感觉到晕眩？
- Yes. - When we first materialised?
- 是的 - 当我们第一次实体化的时候呢？
- I did. - It happened twice.
- 我感觉到了 - 它发生了两次
First, we were in our own transporter chamber, and then we faded.
我们先到了进取号，接着又被传送走了
And then, when we finally materialised, we were here, wherever this is.
当我们最终实体化时，就到了这里
Captain, the transporter chief mentioned a surge of power.
舰长，传送室的负责人提到过能量波动
The transporter lock might have been affected by the ion storm,
传送室或许受到电磁风暴的影响没有完全锁定我们
and we just materialised somewhere else.
我们被传送到了其他地方
Yes, here.
是的，这里
Not our universe, not our ship.
不在我们的宇宙，不在我们的飞船上
Something...
有一些事情是…
...parallel.
…平行的
Parallel universe, coexisting with ours on another dimensional plane.
平行宇宙，在其他维度平面共存的宇宙
Everything's duplicated.
一切都被复制了
Almost.
几乎所有事情
Another Enterprise, Spock with a beard...
另一艘进取号，长胡子的史波克…
Another Captain Kirk, another Dr. McCoy,
另一个寇克舰长，另一个麦考伊医生
- another... - An exchange. If we're here...
- 另一个… - 这是一次换位，如果我们到了这里…
Then our counterparts must have been transporting up
那这个宇宙的我们一定也在传送中
at the exact same time.
在相同的时刻
Similar storms on both universes disrupted the circuits.
在两个宇宙相似的风暴，都扰乱了设备运行
We're here, and they're...
我们到了这里，那他们…
...on our Enterprise.
…一定在我们的进取号上
Probably asking the same questions:
或许问着同样的问题：
"Are we in another universe? And if so, how do we get back to our own?"
“我们在另一个宇宙吗？怎么才能回到原来的宇宙？”
They'll use the computer, and we have to.
他们会用电脑找出答案，我们也必须这么做
What about the Halkans?
那哈克星人怎么办？
We can't let them be destroyed.
我们不能让他们被毁灭
Scotty, can you buy me some time?
史考特，你能为我争取些时间吗？
Get below and short out the main phaser couplings.
到轮机室把主相位炮控制器短路
They'll think the storm blew the circuits.
他们会认为是电磁暴损坏了电路
- Aye, sir. - Then, get on this technology.
- 好的，长官 - 然后，试试这台电脑吧
It's all we have to work with if we want to get back home.
如果我们想要回家，我们就必须这么做
The intercom may be monitored.
内部网络可能被监控了
Use your communicators for private messages.
用你的联络器传送私人信息
- Sub-frequency, and scrambled. - Aye, sir.
- 使用子频率，防止被窃听 - 是，长官
- Lieutenant. - Yes, sir.
- 上尉
Get up to your post.
回到你的岗位上去
Run today's communication from Starfleet Command.
查看今天舰队司令部发出的信息
I want to know my exact orders, and options, if any.
我想知道我下过哪些命令
- Yes, sir. - Bones.
- 是，长官 - 老骨头
Captain, I... I'm...
舰长，我…我…
Uhura, you're the only one who can do it. I'll be right there.
乌乎拉，你是唯一能胜任的人，我稍后到指挥室
Yes, sir.
是，长官
Bones.
老骨头
Let's take a look at the library. We have a lot to learn.
我们来看一下资料，我们有很多东西要学习
Mr. Chekov, phaser setting for planetary target A.
契诃夫先生，相位炮瞄准哈克行星上目标A
Coordinates 712, stroke 4, Mr. Sulu.
苏鲁先生，坐标712，打击力度4
Port batteries locked.
发射电源锁定
Still no interest, Uhura?
乌乎拉，还是对我不理不睬吗？
I could change your mind.
我会改变你的心意
You are away from your post, mister.
长官，你擅离职守了
Is the captain here? Is Spock here?
舰长和史波克都不在
When the cat's away...
山中无老虎…
- Communication status. - No storm damage, sir.
- 报告通信状态 - 长官，没有受到风暴损坏
All stations report normal.
所有部门都报告正常
You're ordered to annihilate the Halkans unless they comply.
你收到命令，如果哈克星人不妥协，就摧毁他们
No alternative.
必须执行
Phasers locked on target A, captain. Approaching optimum range.
舰长，相位炮锁定目标A，正接近最佳攻击距离
Commence fire, captain?
舰长，开火吗？
- Captain? - Stand by, Mr. Sulu.
- 舰长？ - 原地待命，苏鲁先生
I...
我…
I've been ordered to check phaser couplings
我收到命令，过来检查相位炮组
for possible damage by the storm.
是否被风暴损坏了
Do you have authorisation from Security, sir?
长官，你有安全部门的授权吗？
Captain's orders.
我接到的是舰长命令
I'll have to check with Security Chief Sulu, sir.
长官，我必须向安全主管苏鲁核实
Never mind, I'll attend to it.
不必了，我会向他说明的
- Kirk here. - Phaser report, sir. No damage.
- 我是寇克 - 长官，相位炮状况汇报，无损坏
Very good. Thank you, Mr. Scott. Kirk out.
非常好，谢谢，史考特先生，通话结束
Planet's rotation is carrying primary target beyond arc of phaser lock.
行星自转正在使主目标脱离相位炮锁定
Shall I correct orbit to new firing position?
需要我修正轨道到达新的发射位置吗？
No.
不用
- Lock on to secondary city. - Aye, sir.
- 锁定次要城市 - 是，长官
Lieutenant Uhura, contact the Halkan Council. I wish to talk to them again.
乌乎拉上尉，联络哈克星委员会，我想再次和他们对话
- Yes, sir. - Captain?
- 舰长？
This is a new race.
这是一个新的种族
They offer other things of value besides dilithium crystals.
除了双锂晶体，他们还能提供其他珍贵的东西
But it is clear that we cannot expect their cooperation.
但是，很明显，他们不愿意合作
They have refused the Empire.
他们已经拒绝了帝国
Command procedure dictates that we provide the customary example.
我们接到的命令就是按照惯例摧毁哈克星
Secondary target now moving beyond our phaser lock.
次要目标也脱离了相位炮锁定
Put phasers on standby, Mr. Sulu.
苏鲁先生，让相位炮待命
- A serious breach of orders, captain. - I have my reasons.
- 舰长，这是严重违反命令的行为 - 我自有主张
And I'll make them clear to you in my own good time.
当我有空了，会告诉你原因的
Captain, I have the leader of the Halkan Council waiting on channel B.
舰长，哈克委员会的领导在B频道
It is useless to resist us.
抵抗是无用的
We do not resist you.
我们没有抵抗你
You have 12 hours to consider your position.
你有12个小时考虑后果
Twelve years, Captain Kirk, or 12,000.
寇克舰长，即使12年或1万2千年
We are ethically compelled to deny your demand
我们基于道德的考虑
for our dilithium crystals,
拒绝给你提供双锂晶体
for you would use their power to destroy.
因为你会用他们的力量去破坏
We will level your planet, and take what we want.
我们会夷平你的星球，得到我们想要的东西
That is destruction. You will die as a race.
那将是彻底的毁灭，你们整个种族都会灭绝
To preserve what we are.
为了保持我们的人性，我们不惜一切代价
We will not argue. Twelve hours, no more.
谈判到此完毕，你只有12个小时
Close communications, turn phasers off.
关闭通话，关闭相位炮
Aye, sir.
是的，长官
Twelve hours, captain. That is unprecedented.
舰长，你给他们12个小时，这是史无前例的
I shall be in my quarters.
我要到我的船舱去
Lieutenant Uhura,
乌乎拉上尉
have Dr. McCoy and Mr. Scott meet me there.
通知麦考伊医生和史考特先生到船舱见我
Captain, you've placed yourself in a most grave position.
舰长，你这是在自找麻烦
This conduct must be reported.
我一定会报告你的所作所为
You're at liberty to do so, Mr. Spock.
史波克先生，您请便
Deck 5, sir?
长官，你要到5层吗？
So you die, captain, and we all move up in rank.
你就要死了，舰长，我们都会升职的
No one will question the assassination of a captain
没有人会过问一个违背帝国意志的舰长
who has disobeyed prime orders of the Empire.
是如何死的
Captain's log, supplemental.
舰长日志，补充
I command an Enterprise where officers apparently employ
在我领导的进取号上
private henchmen among the crew,
长官们会从船员中雇佣私人追随者
where assassination of superiors is a common means of advancing in rank.
在这里，谋杀上级是晋升的常用手段
Your men, captain. Easy, Farrell.
我是你的人，舰长，放轻松，法瑞尔
- I did your job. Ask the captain. - Sir?
- 我替你们救了舰长，问问他吧 - 长官？
Yes, he did your job.
是的，他确实救了我
Smart boy. Switching to the top dog.
聪明的家伙，懂得见风使舵
Get him out of here.
把他带走
Mr. Chekov was going to make me a chief, sir.
长官，契诃夫先生答应让我做主管
You could make me an officer.
你也应该给我个官做做
- All right, you're working for me. - A commission?
- 好的，你现在是我的人了 - 这是你的承诺吗？
You're in line. You might even make captain.
你会晋升的，你甚至有可能当上舰长
Yes, sir.
是的，长官
Not on my ship.
但不是在我的船上
The booth for this one, sir?
要对这个人用电击吗，长官？
Yes, the booth. Carry on.
是的，电击，去吧
Here. Here, what's this?
等等，这是什么？
It's called blood.
是血
Watch your step. The officers move up by assassination.
千万小心，这里的官员都是靠谋杀晋升的
Chekov tried it on me.
契诃夫就试图谋杀我
Mr. Sulu is security chief, like the ancient Gestapo.
苏鲁先生是安全主管，就像古代的盖世太保
And my Sickbay is a chamber of horrors.
而我的医务室也变得非常恐怖
Two of my assistants were betting on the tolerance of an injured man,
我的两个助手在打赌，受伤的人能承受多少疼痛
how long it would take him to pass out from the pain.
要过多久才能让人昏厥
- Report on technology. - Mostly variations in instrumentation.
- 报告这里的技术情况 - 大部分变化都在仪表上
- Nothing I can't handle. - Star readings?
- 我都能应付 - 太空的情况呢？
Everything's exactly where it should be, except us.
一切都正常，除了我们
Let's find out where we stand.
让我们查查我们在哪里吧
- Computer. - Ready.
- 计算机 - 准备就绪
This is the captain. Record security research
我是舰长，记录一项加密调查
to be classified under my voiceprint or Mr. Scott's.
这项调查只有我或者史考特先生的语音才能解读
Recording.
记录中
Produce all data relevant to the recent ion storm.
记录下所有关于最近遭遇的电磁风暴的数据
Correlate the following hypothesis:
考虑如下的假设：
Could a storm of such magnitude cause a power surge
那种强度的风暴能不能
in the transporter circuits, creating a momentary
在传送室设备中产生能量
interdimensional contact with a parallel universe?
使人暂时和平行宇宙产生跨维度接触？
Affirmative.
确认
At such a moment, could persons in each universe,
在那个时候，在各自宇宙的人
in the act of beaming, transpose with their counterparts
能否通过传送
in the other universe?
与另一宇宙的人换位？
Affirmative.
确认
Could conditions necessary to such an event
这种情况能否使用这艘船的能量
be created artificially, using the ship's power?
人工制造出来？
Affirmative.
确认
Record procedure.
记录下步骤
Scotty, can you do it?
史考特，你能做到吗？
Not by myself. I'll need help.
我一个人不行，我需要帮助
You'd be too conspicuous.
你是舰长，太引人注意了
I'm a doctor, not an engineer.
我是医生，不是工程师
Now you're an engineer.
你现在是工程师了
I'll have to tap the power we need from the warp engines
我要先从曲速引擎中获取需要的能量
and balance it for the four of us.
然后分成4等分
Jim, the way this ship is run,
吉姆，看这艘船管理这么混乱
what kind of people are we in this universe?
这个宇宙的我们是怎样的人？
Let's find out. Computer.
我们来查一查，计算机
Ready.
准备就绪
Read out official record of current command.
报出现任指挥官的经历
Captain James T. Kirk.
舰长，詹姆士·T·寇克
Succeeded to command ISS Enterprise
通过谋杀舰长克里斯托弗·派克
through assassination of Captain Christopher Pike.
成功控制ISS进取号
First action: Suppression of Gorlan uprising
第一次任务：镇压格兰星人起义
through destruction of rebel home planet.
摧毁了反叛者的母星
Second action: Execution of 5,000 colonists on Vega IX.
第二次任务：在织女9行星处决了5000名殖民者
Cancel.
取消
- Now we know. - Captain.
- 现在我们了解了 - 舰长
- We can do it. - Good.
- 我们能做到 - 好的
We have to lay in the automatic-transporter setting.
我们必须把它设置成自动传送
But when we interrupt engine circuits
但当我们打断引擎正常工作
to tie the power increase into the transporter,
将能量导入到传送室时
it'll show up on Sulu's security board.
苏鲁的安全面板上会显示出来
Of course, we'll only need a second.
当然，这只需要一点时间
I'll tell Uhura to create a diversion to distract Sulu's attention at your signal.
我会通知乌乎拉吸引苏鲁的注意力
We'd better get back to our posts. Keep me advised.
我们最好回到各自岗位，保持联络
Jim.
吉姆
If we're here, what do you suppose our counterparts are doing
现在我们在这里，这个宇宙的我们
back in our universe?
在我们的宇宙中在做什么呢？
On our Enterprise.
在我们的进取号上
I order you!
我命令你
Let me go!
放开我
Traitors! Spock, get these men off me!
叛徒，史波克，让这些人放开我
What do you think you're doing, Spock?
史波克，你知道你在做什么吗？
You traitorous pig. I'll hang you up by your Vulcan ears.
你这个叛徒，我要吊起你的瓦肯耳朵
- I'll have you all executed! - I think not.
- 我一定要把你们都处决了 - 我可不这么想
Your authority on this ship is extremely limited, captain.
舰长，你在这艘船上的权威非常有限
The four of you will remain here in the brig, and in custody,
你们四个要被监管在这件舱室里
until I discover how to return you to wherever it is you belong.
直到我想出把你们送回去的方法
Has the whole galaxy gone crazy? What kind of a uniform is this?
这整个星系都疯了吗？这算什么制服？
Where's your beard? What's going on? Where's my personal guard?
你的胡子呢？发生了什么事？我的私人护卫呢？
I can answer none of your questions at this time.
现在我一个问题也回答不了你
All right, Spock.
好吧，史波克
Whatever your game is, I'll play it.
不管你耍什么花样，我都奉陪
You want credits? I'll give them to you. You'll be a rich man.
你想要信贷吗？我会给你的，你会很有钱
A command of your own? I can swing that too.
你想要自己的追随者？我也答应你
Apparently, some kind of transposition has taken place.
很显然，这里发生了某种换位
I find it extremely interesting.
我发现这很有趣
Spock, what is it that will buy you?
史波克，你到底想要什么？
- Power? - Fascinating.
- 权力？ - 有意思
Power, Spock? I can get that for you!
你想要权力吗，史波克？我会给你的
Captain.
舰长
I am pleased that you frustrated Mr. Chekov's plan.
我很高兴你没让契诃夫的计划得逞
I should regret your death.
如果你死了，我会很难过的
- Why? - I do not desire the captaincy.
- 为什么？ - 我不想做舰长
I much prefer my scientific duties,
我更喜欢科学官的职位
and I am, frankly, content to be a lesser target.
而且老实说，我不想成为一个显眼的目标
Logical, as always, Mr. Spock.
史波克，你还是那么有逻辑性
The agony booth is a most effective means of discipline.
肉体电击是最有效的惩罚方法
I presume you've ordered full duration?
你已经下令给他最大强度的电击了？
I haven't decided.
我还没决定
Indeed?
真的吗？
- His act warrants death. - I said, I haven't decided.
- 他的行为够判死刑了 - 我说过了，我还没决定
That is, of course, your affair.
当然，这是你的事情
Captain, may I enquire if you intend to persist
舰长，我能问下你是否还坚持
in your unusual course of action regarding the Halkans?
用反常的行为对待哈克星人？
You heard my orders.
你听到我的命令了
They are, of course, in contradiction to standard Empire procedure.
当然，你的命令不符合帝国的规范
You cannot ignore the consequences.
你不能不考虑后果
Is that a threat?
这是威胁吗？
I do not threaten, captain. I merely state facts.
我没有威胁你，舰长，我只是陈述事实
I have found you to be an excellent officer.
我一直觉得你是个优秀的长官
Our missions together have been both successful and profitable.
我们一起执行的任务都大获全胜，战绩斐然
However, I shall not permit your aberrations
然而我不会允许你反常的行为
to jeopardise my position.
危及到我的职位
Spock...
史波克…
...do you think we should destroy the Halkans?
…你觉得我们应该摧毁哈克星人吗？
Terror must be maintained, or the Empire is doomed.
暴力手段必须维持，不然帝国将会灭亡
- It is the logic of history. - Conquest is easy. Control is not.
- 这是历史的逻辑 - 征服容易，但是控制艰难
We may have bitten off more than we can chew.
我们征服的太多，已经超出了控制的能力
Captain, I do not wish to find myself opposing you.
舰长，我不想反对你
But if you continue on your present course,
但是如果你继续像现在一样
this confusing, inexplicable behaviour...
行事那么反常、令人费解…
Is my concern, not yours.
这是我该担心的问题，不是你的
You would find me a formidable enemy.
你会发现我变成了强大的敌人
I am aware of that, captain.
我了解，舰长
I trust that you are aware of the reverse.
反过来，我相信你也了解我的实力
Orders, sir?
长官，你有什么命令吗？
Release Chekov. Confine him to quarters.
把契诃夫放了，把他关押在监视室里
Yes, sir.
是，长官
That ought to hold him for about six hours.
这剂药能让他昏迷6个小时
I fell asleep.
我睡着了
We had quite a time in the Chem Lab picking up after the storm.
风暴过后，我们花了很长时间收拾化学实验室
Nothing compared to your day, I gather.
我想，谁也比不上你今天过得精彩
I heard about Chekov.
我听说契诃夫的事了
He gambled. I won.
他铤而走险，我赢了
You got lucky.
你走运而已
I'm surprised that you could be caught off guard that way.
我很惊讶你脱离了警卫
I was preoccupied.
我掉以轻心了
You're still in trouble with Starfleet Command.
你和星舰司令部之间还有麻烦
What you've got in mind this time is beyond me.
这次你心里想什么可难倒我了
You're scheming, of course.
当然，你有你的计划
The Halkans have something you want.
哈克星上有你想要的东西
Or is it all some clever means to advance you to the admiralty?
或者这只是你进一步高升的台阶？
Kirk.
寇克
- The cabinet itself? - Further than that, if I'm successful.
- 你想进内阁吗？ - 远不止那个，如果我成功的话
Really?
真的？
Well, you must know what you're doing.
嗯，你一定知道自己在做什么
You always do.
你一向如此
If I'm to be the woman of a Caesar...
如果我要成为凯撒的女人…
...can't I know what you're up to?
…我怎么会不知道你要干什么呢？
- Kirk here. - Mr. Spock, captain.
- 我是寇克 - 舰长，我是史波克
Yes?
有什么事吗？
I've received a private communication from Starfleet Command.
我收到了星舰司令部发来的私人消息
I am committing a breach of regulations
让你知道消息的内容
by informing you of its contents.
已经违反了规定
Yes, Mr. Spock?
嗯，史波克
I'm instructed to wait until planet dawn over principal target
我被告知，在阳光照射到主目标之前
to permit you to carry out our mission.
我会允许你执行任务
And if I don't?
如果我不呢？
In that event, I am ordered to kill you
如果那样的话，我被命令杀死你
and to proceed against the Halkans as the new captain of the Enterprise.
作为进取号的新舰长，摧毁哈克星
Captain's log, stardate unknown.
舰长日志，星历未知
We are trapped in a savage parallel universe
我们被困在了一个野蛮的平行宇宙里
from which we must escape within four hours
在4个小时内我们必须逃离这里
or I will face a death sentence at Mr. Spock's hands.
不然史波克就会杀掉我
Let's drink a toast to Spock,
让我们为史波克干杯
the only man aboard with the decency to warn you.
他是这艘船上唯一体面警告你的人
And he'll die for it.
他会为此而死
You'll never find another man like him.
你再也找不到像他那样的人了
I don't intend to kill him.
我不会杀他
Are you going to act against the Halkans before the deadline?
你会在最后期限前对付哈克星人吗？
No. But I'll avoid killing Spock.
不，但是我也会避免杀死史波克
Just get him out of the way? He and his men?
你要让他不插手这件事？他和他的属下？
I'll get out of his way.
我会让他不插手这件事的
Shall I activate the Tantalus field?
需要我激活坦塔罗斯场吗？
You'll at least want to monitor him, won't you?
最起码你要监视他，是不是？
Yes.
是的
I hate this thing.
我恨这个东西
- It's not that bad. - Of course not. It made you captain.
- 也没那么坏 - 当然不，是它让你当上舰长的
How many enemies have you simply wiped out of existence
轻轻的按下按钮
by the touch of a button?
你靠这个消灭了多少敌人？
Fifty? A hundred?
50个？100个？
And I always thought that was funny.
我一直觉得这很滑稽
The great, powerful Captain Kirk, who owes everything
伟大的、强大的寇克舰长
to some unknown alien scientist and a plundered laboratory.
他的一切都是拜未知的外星科技所赐
Well, if you don't take advantage of your opportunities...
嗯，如果你不好好利用这机会…
You don't rise to the command of a starship.
你不会成为舰长
Or even higher.
或者更高的职位
That magnificent mind of his.
他的心肠很好
But it can't protect him from this.
但是这不能保护他免除伤害
I press it, and he dies.
我按下这个按钮，他就会死
Now?
现在吗？
You really mean it.
你真的要那样做
It doesn't matter.
没关系
If Spock fails his order, he'll be killed anyway.
如果史波克没有遵守命令，无论如何都会被杀死
I'll see to it that the circumstances of his failure will clear him.
我要确保他不遵守命令也能保全自己
You're not even afraid of Starfleet Command.
你甚至都不害怕星舰司令部
Can your scheme bring you that much power so quickly?
你的计划能这么快得获得权力吗？
And what about me? How does Marlena fit in?
那我呢？玛丽安娜该如何自处呢？
How does Marlena want to fit in?
玛丽安娜想要怎么自处呢？
- Scotty. - Scotty here, sir.
- 史考特 - 长官，我是史考特
We have to get out of here within three hours.
我们必须在3个小时内离开这里
Spock has orders to kill me unless I complete the military mission.
史波克已经得到命令，除非我执行任务，否则就要杀了我
- We've got another deadline too, sir. - Explain.
- 长官，我们这也遇到了一个最后期限 - 说明情况
The two-way matter transmission
双路的物质传送
affected the local field density between the universes
影响了宇宙中局部场密度
and it's increasing. We've got to move fast.
而且一直在增加，我们必须要快速行动
- How fast? - A half hour, at the most.
- 要多快？ - 最多一个半小时
If we miss?
如果我们赶不及呢？
We couldn't get out of here in a century.
我们永远也不能离开这里了
Now, we're ready to bridge power from the engines to the transporter.
我们准备连通引擎和传送室，传导能量了
You've got to get down there and free the board so we can lock in.
你要下来设置控制面板，这样我们才能连接到传送室
Give me about ten minutes.
给我十分钟时间
I've gotta complete a few more computations.
我还要完成一些计算
All right, I'll be in the Transporter Room in ten minutes.
好的，我会在10分钟内到传送室
- I'll meet you in the Sickbay afterward. - Aye, sir.
- 稍后我会在医务室和你汇合 - 好的，长官
- Computer. - Ready.
- 计算机 - 准备就绪
Explain computer activity in the Engineering section.
解释下工程部计算机的动态
A security research is in progress.
一项加密调查正在运行
Who is conducting the research?
谁在做调查？
The captain and Mr. Scott.
舰长和史考特先生
What is the nature of the research?
这项调查的内容是什么？
Program is classified under voice-index lock.
这项调查已经被语音加密
Why are you monitoring my communications, Mr. Sulu?
苏鲁先生，你为什么要监视我的通话？
My security board has detected extensive use of computer, Mr. Spock.
史波克先生，我的监控板监测到计算机活动
I was about to inform you.
我正要通知你
It's not hard to guess the nature of your order from Starfleet Command.
要猜出你收到的星舰司令部命令的内容并不难
I suggest a connection, the captain suspects.
我猜，舰长被怀疑了
He's working on escape or defence.
他想要逃跑或者叛变
That is my concern.
那是我该考虑的问题
Correct, it's your play. I hope you succeed,
当然了，这是你的事情，我希望你能赢
because the order would fall on me next.
因为同样的命令下一次就会发给我了
And you know how Captain Kirk's enemies have a habit of...
而且你要知道寇克舰长的敌人…
...disappearing.
…最后都失踪了
If I am successful, you see yourself a step nearer to the captaincy.
如果我成功了，你也会更接近舰长头衔
I do not want to command the Enterprise.
我不想领导进取号
But if it should befall me,
但是如果责任落到我身上
I suggest you remember
我建议你记住
that my operatives would avenge my death.
我的追随者会为我复仇的
And some of them
而他们中间有些人
are Vulcans.
是瓦肯人
Oiling my traps, darling.
亲爱的，来给我的背擦油
I'm afraid I'm a little out of practise.
我担心，我有点表现失常了
Maybe that's what happened to us.
或许这就是我们之间的感情
It's very hard for a working officer to shine as a woman every minute.
让一个女船员每时每刻 都像一个女人那样光鲜耀眼真的很难
- And you demand perfection. - I've never seen perfection.
- 而你苛求完美 - 我从没见过完美的事物
But no woman could come closer to it.
但是没有任何女人比你更接近完美了
I remember when you used to talk that way.
我还记得你过去说这些话的样子
- I still do. - Prove it.
- 我依然未变 - 那就证明它
- I've gotta go. - Ship's business?
- 我要走了 - 船上的事务吗？
An important task on the crew deck?
要在甲板上宣布一项重要任务？
Well, I guess it's over.
嗯，我想我们之间完了
Commander Kenner will take me temporarily. He's made that quite clear.
指挥官肯尼会带我走，他已经说得很明白了
I'll call a yeoman to help me with my things.
我会找个仆人帮我收拾东西
You don't have to do that.
你不必那么做
Are you feeling sorry for me?
你对我感到歉疚吗？
Do I see hesitation in your eyes, about anything?
我在你的眼中可曾看到过犹豫？
I want one thing, captain:
舰长，我只想要一件事：
Transfer me.
传送我
On the Enterprise, I am humiliated.
在进取号上，我被羞辱了
On another ship, I can hunt fresh game.
在另一艘船上，我可以重新开始
I've got my rank, and...
我已经得到了官衔，并且…
Don't I?
难道不是吗？
I've been a captain's woman and I like it.
我曾经是一个舰长的女人，我喜欢那种感觉
I'll be one again, if I have to go though every officer in the fleet.
我会再次成为舰长的女人，即使我要走遍整个舰队
You could.
你可以的
I simply meant...
我只是想说…
...that you could be anything you want to be.
…你可以做你想要成为的任何人
It's been a long time since you've kissed me like that.
你好长时间没有像那样吻我了
You're a stranger.
你不是寇克
Mercy to the Halkans, mercy to Spock,
你同情哈克星人，同情史波克
to me.
同情我
Am I your woman?
我是你的女人吗？
You're the captain's woman until he says you're not.
除非你拒绝，你一直是舰长的女人
Uhura.
乌乎拉
Yes, captain.
是的，舰长
Scotty's signal should be coming through any moment now.
史考特的信号随时都可能发出
- You know what to do. - I've got a pretty good idea, sir.
- 你知道该怎么做 - 长官，我有一个好主意
- Keep Sulu's attention off that board. - I'll do my best, sir.
- 转移苏鲁的注意力，不让他盯着监控板 - 长官，我会尽力的
Good luck. Kirk out.
祝好运，通话结束
You aren't very persistent, Mr. Sulu.
苏鲁先生，你没有坚持
The game has rules. You're ignoring them.
游戏都是有规则的，你忽视了他们
I protest, and you come back.
我拒绝了，你要再追求我
You didn't come back.
你没有继续追求
- Now you're making sense. - I was getting bored.
- 你现在终于开窍了 - 我很无聊
Of course, this isn't the time.
当然了，现在这个时间不合适
Any time's a good time.
任何时间都是合适的
I'm afraid I changed my mind again.
恐怕我又改变主意了
You take a lot of chances, lieutenant.
上尉，你错过了很多次机会
So do you, mister.
你也是，先生
So do you.
你也是
Take over for me.
接替我的工作
Mr. Scott.
史考特先生
All clear. On my way to Sickbay.
一切正常，我正在去医务室的路上
Now it's up to the captain.
现在就看舰长的了
You will please restrict your movements, captain.
舰长，你的行动应该受到限制
What are you doing?
你在做什么？
Are you gonna shoot me now, Spock? I thought I had until dawn.
史波克，你现在要开枪吗？我还以为可以等到黎明
I shall make that decision.
我做了决定
Since you returned from the planet,
自从你从哈克星上回来
you have behaved in a most atypical and illogical manner.
你就表现地极其反常
- I want to know why. - Shoot. You're wasting time.
- 我想知道原因 - 开枪吧，你在浪费时间
I shall not waste time with you.
我不会和你浪费时间
You're too inflexible, too disciplined, once you've made up your mind.
一旦你下定决定，你就会变得太遵守纪律，顽固不懂变通
But Dr. McCoy has a plenitude of human weaknesses.
但是麦考伊医生有着丰富的人性缺点
Sentimental, soft.
敏感，性格软弱
You may not tell me what I want to know,
你或许不会告诉我真相
but he will.
但是他会的
You're running a big risk, Spock.
史波克，你这是冒险
I have the phaser, captain.
舰长，我带着手枪
And I do not intend to simply disappear
而且我也不想
as so many of your opponents have in the past.
像过去你的对手一样莫名其妙地失踪
If you please.
如果你愿意
Sickbay.
到医务室去
Yes, of course. The entire landing party.
哦，当然了，整个登陆队伍都到齐了
Captain, stand over there. Doctor, it is time for answers.
舰长，站到那边去，医生，是时候告诉我真相了
How much time, Scotty?
史考特，还有多少时间？
Hardly 15 minutes, sir.
不到15分钟了，长官
The field density between the two universes
两个宇宙之间的场密度
is starting to close very fast.
开始要关闭了，速度很快
Help me get him on the table.
帮我把他抬到床上
Come on, help me get him on the table!
快点，帮我把他抬到床上
He'll die without immediate treatment.
如果不及时治疗，他会死的
Everything laid in, Scotty?
史考特，都准备好了吗？
The time lag, so the operator can get into the transporter chamber?
操作时间间隔有没有设好？ 让操作的人能有时间进到传送室
All laid in, sir.
长官，都准备好了
Come on, McCoy, we're taking a chance on not getting back home.
来吧，麦考伊，你这么做我们可能都回不了家了
We'll get home. This won't take long.
我们会回家的，这不需要很长时间
Fourteen minutes. We've got to go!
还剩14分钟，我们一定要走
You shut up!
你闭嘴
I can save his life.
我能救他
Do you want me to stop, Jim? It'll only take a minute.
吉姆，你不希望我救他吗？这花不了多少时间
He is very much like our own Mr. Spock, isn't he?
他和我们的史波克很像，是不是？
You've got that minute.
好吧，给你时间救他
A little time, he'll live.
只需要一点时间，他就能活过来
What is this, Mr. Sulu?
苏鲁，你这是要做什么？
Mr. Spock has orders to kill you, captain.
舰长，史波克先生下令要杀你
He will succeed.
他会继任舰长
Apparently, you will also appear to have killed him...
但显然，在经过激烈的搏斗之后…
...after a fierce battle.
…你已经杀了他
Regrettable, but it will leave me in command.
很遗憾，但最后是我掌权了
Captain, we've barely got ten minutes.
舰长，我们只有10分钟了
Let's go, Bones.
我们走，老骨头
I can't let him die, Jim.
吉姆，我不能让他死
You get to the Transporter Room, make sure it's clear.
你们去传送室，做好准备
- I'll be there in five minutes. - No longer.
- 五分钟内我会到那里的 - 你只有五分钟时间
I guarantee it.
我保证
Now, go on, please.
好吧，我们走
Why did the captain let me live?
为什么舰长没杀死我？
Our minds are merging, doctor.
医生，我们的思维在融合
Our minds are one.
我们的思维合二为一
I feel what you feel.
我能感受到你的感受
I know what you know.
我能知道你的事情
A friend.
她是我的朋友
Activate the transporter.
激活传送器
You saved us back in Sickbay, with the Tantalus field.
你在医务室用坦塔罗斯场救了我
- Take me with you. - I can't.
- 带我走吧 - 我不能
I'm sorry. Our power's balanced for four.
抱歉，能量最多能分4份
There's no guarantee we'll make it with five. All could die.
分成5份时就不能保证了，我们可能都会死
- Scotty? - It's working, sir.
- 史考特？ - 工作正常，长官
- But there are only three of you. - One is coming.
- 但是你们只有三个人 - 最后一个正在赶来
I'd help you if I could, Marlena. Believe that.
玛丽安娜，我真的很想帮你
If you kill us, you'll still stay.
你杀了我们，也不能离开这里
Where's McCoy?
麦考伊在哪里？
- Time, Scotty? - Five minutes, sir.
- 还有多少时间，史考特？ - 长官，还有5分钟
Do you know what they'll do to me?
你知道他们会怎么对我吗？
The power is cut, sir. They're on to us!
长官，电力中断了，他们发现我们了
- Auxiliary? - Aye, it's available.
- 辅助电力呢？ - 辅助电力可以使用
- Can you bridge to your setup? - I can get us the power,
- 你能直接把能量传到传输室吗？ - 我能把能量传送过来
but the automatic setting is linked to the transporter main.
但是自动设置是连接到传输室主电源的
If we bypass,
如果我们绕过自动设置
it means that someone has got to operate the controls manually.
那就意味着需要某个人手动操作控制台
- One of us will have to stay. - I'll stay, captain.
- 我们中有人必须留下 - 舰长，我留下吧
Get to the transporter chamber. You too, Uhura.
到传输室去，乌乎拉，你也是
Jim.
吉姆
That's an order, Scotty.
史考特，这是命令
Aye, captain.
是，舰长
What about me?
那我呢？
McCoy...
麦考伊…
I cut the transporter power.
我切断了传输室的能量
It was necessary to delay your beam-out until I could arrive.
这样我才能赶上你们
Engineering, reactivate main transporter circuits.
工程部，将主传输室电路复位
You're a man of integrity in both universes, Mr. Spock.
史波克，你在两个宇宙中都是那么正直
You must return to your universe, I must have my captain back.
你必须回到你的宇宙中去，我必须让我的舰长回来
I'll operate the transporter.
我来操作传送装置
You have two minutes and ten seconds.
你还剩2分10秒
For that time, I have something to say.
在走之前，我有一些话要说
How long before the Halkan prediction of galactic revolt is realised?
哈克星人预言的起义什么时候出现？
- Approximately 240 years. - The inevitable outcome?
- 大约240年之后 - 不可避免的结果是什么？
The Empire shall be overthrown, of course.
当然是帝国被推翻
The illogic of waste, Mr. Spock.
史波克先生，这期间的浪费是不合逻辑的
The waste of lives, potential resources, time.
生命、资源、时间的浪费
I submit to you that your Empire is illogical
我告诉你，你的帝国的存在是不合逻辑的
because it cannot endure. I submit...
因为它不能持续
...that you are illogical to be a willing part of it.
…你乐意成为其中的一员也是不合逻辑的
You have one minute and 23 seconds.
你还有1分23秒
If change is inevitable, predictable, beneficial,
如果改变是不可避免的，可预测的，有益的
doesn't logic demand that you be a part of it?
你成为其中一员难倒不合逻辑吗？
One man cannot summon the future...
一个人无法改变未来…
But one man can change the present.
但可以改变现在
Be the captain of this Enterprise, Mr. Spock.
史波克，做这艘进取号的舰长吧
Find a logical reason for sparing the Halkans, and make it stick.
找一个合乎逻辑的原因放过哈克星，把它作为基地
Push till it gives.
推动革命直到帝国放弃
You can defend yourself better than any man in the fleet.
你可以变得比司令部任何人都强大
Captain, get in the chamber!
舰长，快进传送室
What about it, Spock?
史波克，你觉得怎么样呢？
The man must also have the power.
那个人还需要别的力量
In my cabin
在我的船舱里
is a device that will make you invincible.
有一种东西能让你变得无法战胜
- Indeed? - What will it be?
- 真的吗？ - 那会是什么呢？
Past or future? Tyranny or freedom? It's up to you.
过去或未来，暴政或自由，都取决于你
It is time.
你们该走了
In every revolution, there is one man with a vision.
在每一场革命中，都需要一个有远见的人
Captain Kirk, I shall consider it.
寇克舰长，我会考虑的
- Spock. - Welcome home, captain.
- 史波克 - 舰长，欢迎回家
What I don't understand is how you were able
我不明白你怎么会
to identify our counterparts so quickly.
那么快地分辨出另一个宇宙中的我们
It was far easier for you, as civilised men, to behave like barbarians
你们作为文明人，想要表现的野蛮
than it was for them, as barbarians, to behave like civilised men.
要比他们作为野蛮人表现得文明，容易得多
I assume they returned to their Enterprise
我认为在你出现在这里的时候
at the same time you appeared here?
他们也回到了他们的进取号
Probably. However, that Jim Kirk will find a few changes,
或许吧，然而，那个吉姆·寇克会发现一些改变
if I read my Spocks correctly.
如果我真正了解了另一个宇宙的史波克
Jim, I think I liked him with a beard better.
吉姆，我觉得我更喜欢他有胡子的样子
Gave him character.
让他更有个性
Of course, almost any change would be a distinct improvement.
当然了，几乎任何改变都有好处
What worries me is the easy way
更让我担心的是
his counterpart fitted into that other universe.
另一个宇宙的史波克那么轻易的就融入了群体
I always thought Spock was a bit of a pirate at heart.
我一直觉得史波克内心有一点海盗情节
Indeed, gentlemen. May I point out that I had opportunity
确实，先生们，我也要指出我有机会
to observe your counterparts here quite closely.
密切关注另一个宇宙中的你们
They were brutal, savage, unprincipled, uncivilised, treacherous.
他们残酷、野蛮、没有原则、未开化
In every way, splendid examples of homo sapiens,
从任何角度看，都是未进化人类的杰出代表
the very flower of humanity.
人类中的奇葩
I found them quite refreshing.
我发现他们很不一样
I'm not sure, but I think we've been insulted.
似乎我觉得我们被侮辱了
I'm sure.
我确定
Captain Kirk?
寇克舰长
- Lieutenant... Lieutenant? - Marlena Moreau.
- 上尉…你叫什么名字？ - 玛丽安娜·梦露
I was just assigned last week.
我上周刚被分配到进取号上
All right, lieutenant. Carry on.
好的，上尉，继续工作吧
Met her before, captain?
舰长，以前见过她吗？
Why do you ask?
你为什么会这么问？
Your reaction. One of recognition?
你的反应，像是认识她的样子
Oh, no. No, no, we haven't met before...
哦，没有，我们从前没见过…
...exactly.
…实际上
She just seemed a nice, likeable girl.
她看起来像一个漂亮、可爱的女孩
I think we could become friends.
我想我们能成为朋友
It's possible.
这很可能